Sam Blank

Boston, MA | sblan45@gmail.com | 617-894-4194

https://github.com/samblank45 | https://samblank45.github.io | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sam-blank45/

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Web developer and military veteran with extensive experience in leadership, communication, teamwork, and problem-solving. My training required adapting the constructs of larger guidelines to unique problems quickly and collaboratively in order to maintain safety for all teammates. I apply these lessons in creativity and focus to web development which allows me to write efficient and effective code.

SKILLS

Technical: Ruby, Rails, Vue.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, APIs, Pair-Programming, Testing,

Object-Oriented Programming, Bootstrap **Additional**: Hebrew (conversational)

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer | Actualize

April 2020 - August 2020

- Sharsheret: Sharsheret: personally built a web app for new immigrants to Israel that allows users to connect with each other through a messaging system. Users also have the ability to create events and attend other user's events. Built in Ruby on Rails and Vue.js modifying Bootstrap and JavaScript transition elements.
- **Bootcamp:** Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
 - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
 - Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
 - Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styles results, incorporated libraries and themes

Front End Developer | First Step Coding

January 2020 - February 2020

- Bootcamp: Learned the basics of coding including HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Jquery.
 - Focused extensively on Javascript through Repl.it and pair programming.
 - Built and created a frontend app using an API and Jquery.

ParaTrooper/Reservist | Israel Defense Forces

October 2015 - Present

- Served as a leader for the team by advancing first and providing cover fire.
- Conducted patrols and missions around the country in order to maintain and complete security objectives.
- Performed monthly on-field communication exercises that enhanced group cohesion.

Facilities Maintenance Manager | 119 BSR Realty

June 2006 - March 2020

- Maintained the plumbing and electrical aspects of the building.
- Collaborated on space modifications and renovations throughout the building for 90+ commercial tenants.

Cycurity | Social Media Manager

February 2017 - June 2019

- Influenced thousands through educational messages by raising awareness on issues including modern day slavery and migrant worker abuse through a coordinated campaign on Twitter.
- Crafted hundreds of messages daily using specific content and tone resulting in changed users' behavior.

EDUCATION